Chicks in Chains - where they come from this is... Fun!
Black Mama, White Mama is a action, crime,
thriller film directed by Eddie Romero.
When two troublemaking female prisoners (one a revolutionary, the other a former harem-girl)
can't seem to get along, they are chained together and extradited for safekeeping.
The women, still chained together, stumble, stab, and cat-fight their way across the
wilderness, igniting a bloody shootout between gangsters and a group of revolutionaries.
Lee Daniels, played by Pam Grier.
Karen Brent, played by Margaret Markov.
Ruben, played by Sid Haig.
Matron Densmore, played by Lynn Borden.
Ernesto, played by Zaldy Zshornack.
Warden Logan, played by Laurie Burton.
Black Mama White Mama, also known as Women in Chains (US reissue title), Hot, Hard and Mean (original 1974 UK title) and Chained Women
(1977 UK reissue title), is a 1973 women in prison film directed by Eddie Romero and starring Pam Grier and Margaret Markov.
The film has elements of blaxploitation.
The movie was reportedly inspired by the 1958 film The Defiant Ones.
Set in an unspecified Latin American country referred to only as "the island",
the movie was shot in the Philippines for budgetary purposes.
The film explores themes of sexual abuse, women's prison,
prison escape, jungle, racial tension.
The tone is emotional and intense.